JakeStuder

Front-End Developer/Web Designer

647.300.6678

jakestuder 68@gmail.com

CHARACTER

Adaptable Accurate Dependable Highly motivated Loyal Personable Professional Prompt Proven leader Self-sufficient

WEB TECHNOLOGY

HTML 5

CSS

JSON

Bootstrap

Python

jsxGraph

JavaScript

MAMP / XAMPP

Google Analytics

GIT / Repositories

AODA compliance

mathML / mathJax

PHP

Brightspace

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a passionate designer and developer with over 15 years of successful experience on diverse teams connecting the world of business to cyberspace. I pride myself on my problem solving ability and implementation of both technical and aesthetic skill to deliver prompt, high caliber solutions to complex business challenges. Personality profiles indicate that I excel in attention to detail, structure, personal relationships and dependability. In all my roles, I have far exceeded expectation and left a positive impact far outlasting my tenure.

EXPERIENCE

TV Ontario (TVO) Toronto, ON

(3 years)

Web Production Artist

2017-2020

- Developed streamlined system to upgrade a python parser which converted HTML code exported from InDesign into a near-finished course layout, drastically improving both production time and code quality of courses.
- · Worked with Curriculum, Learning Experience Design and Web Development teams to continually create new processes and work patterns to build efficiency into existing processes as well as those newly required.
- Strategized closely with Manager of Course Production on project management and reporting tools to track progress against goals and to deliver deadlines to meet the tight Project Charter timelines and expectations.
- Thoroughly trained 16 new hire employees with varying skill level and at multiple times on software, processes and design.
- · Created new widgets within the Bootstrap framework to more efficiently and aesthetically display course content for ease of use and readability for users.
- Produced multiple 110 hour courses that met AODA compliance standards.
- · Recorded voice-overs for animations.

Toronto ICC Toronto, ON

(3 years)

Church Facilitator / Counselor

2014-2017

- · Provided intimate guidance, advice and planning for both individuals and families in all areas such as parenting, finances, life skills, mental and emotional support, physical fitness and marriage relationships.
- Conducted and led both small and large group meetings to increase awareness in a variety of areas including but not limited to those aforementioned.
- Established the Toronto ICC as a government recognized charity organization in Ontario.
- Successfully planned and executed both small and large scale fundraisers ranging from several hundred dollars to over \$30,000 for groups such as TICC and M.E.R.C.Y Worldwide.
- · Coached and inspired many groups in volunteer efforts from food collection for the homeless, blood drives, cleaning and repairing homeless shelters and assisting the Scott Mission summer camp for kids.

SOFTWARE

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign Dreamweaver Premier Pro After Effects Captivate Audition MS Office Pro Tools / Audacity

Ultrafabrics, LLC New York City (USA)

(5 years)

Systems Analyst

- Created very first company intranet system using Bootstrap framework. This grew to be a cross-departmental tool for record keeping, inventory, communication and scheduling.
- Interviewed each department to determine major needs and implemented into intranet.
- Set up and monitored Google Analytics for reporting at staff meetings to aide future order placement, customer retention and sales.
- · Conducted sales-focused employee Lunch and Learn sessions on utilization of the Intranet system in order to streamline day to day production and profit margin.

Senior Graphic Designer

2009-2011

 Designed all in-house collateral material including but not limited to fabric binders, colour cards, brochures, trade show booths, postcards and e-communications.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Fine Arts 2004 - Miami University, Ohio (USA)

jakestuder68.github.io

References available upon request

Comdata (Ceridian) Nashville, TN (USA)

(2 years)

(2 years)

Graphic Designer

2007-2009

- Created interfaces for Point-of-Sale (POS) terminals at truckstops throughout the U.S.A.
- · Maintained multiple data-driven web pages to ensure most current information available to customer database.
- Designed magazine ads, large format tradeshow graphics, gift cards, brochures and logos.
- Headed United Way creative campaign each year for company fundraiser.

Affiliated Computer Jr. Graphic Designer Services (ACS) Brentwood, TN (USA)

2005-2007

- Designed multi-ad campaigns for customers based on their vision.
- Designed web banners, e-blasts, brochures, billboards and trade show booths.
- Provided creative ideas and strategy for transportation clients and in one case, saved a client from going to a competitor they were so please with my campaign design.